Rob Trudell

Android Developer

Pinconning, MI | (989) 313-7080 | robertrudell@gmail.com | robtrudell.com

Summary

Software developer with over 3 years of experience and a passion for mobile development. Seeking an opportunity to work with a company that shares my core values of integrity, reliability, and compassion, where I can contribute my skills to projects that have a direct impact on the company's success and learn from experienced team members.

Experience

Android Developer

Innowise| Remote | June 2022 - Present

- Developed and maintained mobile apps for a variety of clients using tools like Jetpack Compose, Gradle, and Flutter
- Worked closely with cross-functional teams to create user-friendly and engaging experiences
- Contributed by adding new features and bug fixes leading to improved app performance, enhanced user engagement, and ultimately increased revenue
- Created realtime databases and user authentication features to applications using Firebase
- Implemented APIs like Dagger/Hilt, Retrofit, and Timber to applications

Freelance Software Developer

Upwork | Remote | January 2020 - May 2022

- Created websites for a variety of clients using JavaScript, React, Wordpress, and Shopify
- Implemented databases with tools like MySQL, AWS, and Firebase
- Created and contributed to a number of mobile projects including Android native applications and IOS applications using Flutter

Product Owner | Financial Planner

FormulaFolios | Grand Rapids, MI | May 2016 - December 2019

- Worked closely with the software development team to implement financial concepts into the firm's proprietary financial planning software
- Assisted in the company's growth helping them achieve Inc Magazine's 10th fastest growing private company in the US in 2017

Education

Western Governors University

Millcreek, UT (Remote) | 2020-2023 Bachelors of Science in Software Engineering

Ferris State University

Big Rapids, MI | 2012-2016 Bachelors of Science in Finance Cum Laude

Associate Android Developer Certification | Google | 2023

Skills

Programming Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Java, Kotlin

IDEs: Android Studio, Visual Studio

Frameworks: Jetpack Compose, React Native, React, Flutter

Tools: Android SDK, Git, Github, Gradle, Chrome Dev Tools, ChatGPT/Bard, Dagger/Hilt,

Retrofit, Timber

Databases: MySQL, Firebase, Room

Concepts: UI/UX, development life cycles, testing and debugging

Links

• Website: robtrudell.com

• Github: https://github.com/robtrudell

- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/robtrudell/
- Android App Project:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.robtrudell.tipify

 "Tifpify" - A fully responsive, minimalistic, and clean Android application that calculates the tip amount based on your inputted bill amount and tip percentage. Offers dynamic feedback on whether the tip is poor, good, great, or amazing.